<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>csaybar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on csaybar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Download the GLC30 product for Peru and Ecuador</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/10/10/landuseperu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/10/10/landuseperu/</guid>
      <description>Land Cover information is fundamental for environmental change studies, land resource management, sustainable development, and many other societal benefits. In Google Earth Engine existing different coarse Land use/cover products (e.g. MCD12Q1-500m) that are not able to capture the most significant human impacts on land systems due to its spatial resolution. Therefore, this short post aims to introduce and explain step by step how to download the GLC30 a relative new Global Land Cover product at 30-meter spatial resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Earth Engine with Tensorflow II - U-Net</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/06/21/eetf2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/06/21/eetf2/</guid>
      <description>This notebook has been inspired by the Chris Brown &amp;amp; Nick Clinton EarthEngine + Tensorflow presentation. It shows the step by step how to integrate Google Earth Engine and TensorFlow 2.0 in the same pipeline (EE-&amp;gt;Tensorflow-&amp;gt;EE).
  OBS: I will assume reader are already familiar with the basic concepts of Machine Learning and Convolutional Networks. If it is doesn’t, I firstly highly recommend taking the deep learning coursera specialization available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Earth Engine with Tensorflow I - DNN</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/05/30/eetf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/05/30/eetf/</guid>
      <description>This notebook has been inspired by the Chris Brown &amp;amp; Nick Clinton EarthEngine + Tensorflow presentation. It shows the step by step how to integrate Google Earth Engine and TensorFlow 2.0 in the same pipeline (EE-&amp;gt;Tensorflow-&amp;gt;EE).
  Topics Create a training/testing dataset (in a TFRecord format) using Earth Engine. Create functions for parse data (TFRecord -&amp;gt; tf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head Start Data Science I: Titanic Challenge</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/05/19/titanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/05/19/titanic/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction The Titanic challenge is an excellent way to practice the necessary skills required for ML. In my first attempts, I blindly applied a well-known ML method (Lightgbm); however, I couldn’t go up over the Top 20% :(. To have success in this competition you need to realize an acute feature engineering that takes into account the distribution on train and test dataset. This post is the perfect opportunity to share with you my Python package preml and show how can you BEAT THE 97% OF LB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create 3D Interactive choropleth map in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/12/plotlyformaps_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/12/plotlyformaps_i/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction A Choropleth map is a thematic map in which areas are colored considering the quantitative measurement of a variable, such as population density or gross domestic product.
There are a lot of libraries in R (and of course in Python too) that perform it efficiently. However, I feel that ggplot2 offers the fastest and most friendly way. Don’t you believe me? Look at this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raster resampling in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/05/resample/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/05/resample/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction A typical workflow for earth analysts always will have to do with several spatial data sources (e.g. Sentinel, MODIS and Landsat) each one with a particular extent and pixel resolution. Resampling is the technique used to homogenize these spatial attributes.
Image obtained from here
 This post demonstrates how easy and incredibly fast is resampling gridded data in R using either the raster and gdalUtils packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>How can I help you? Thank you for visiting my site. Please feel free to contact me. I am always interested in making academic and outreach collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/</guid>
      <description>Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.
1. WHAT TO DO IF I HAVE STILL NOT RECEIVED THE ORDER? Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Complete list of publications on Google Scholar
Book  Andrade, M.F., Moreno, I., Calle, J.M., Ticona, L., Blacutt, L., Lavado-Casimiro, W., Sabino, E., Huerta, A., Aybar, C., Hunziker, S. and Brönnimann, S., 2018. Climate and extreme events from the Central Altiplano of Peru and Bolivia.  Refereed Journal Articles  Aybar, C., Fernández, C., Huerta, A., Lavado, W., Vega, F., &amp;amp; Felipe-Obando, O. (2019). Construction of a high-resolution gridded rainfall dataset for Peru from 1981 to the present day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>The course EEwPython is a series of Jupyter notebook (colab) to learn Google Earth Engine (GEE) with python. EEwPython is structured in two parts. The first one is an adaptation from all Google Earth Engine Documentation to be able to run in python, and the second one is a recompilation of different reproducible examples. If you want to contribute with EEwPython, do not doubt to keep in touch with us. All the material is released under the Apache 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>