<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>raster on csaybar</title>
    <link>/tags/raster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in raster on csaybar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/raster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>rgee example #2: Satellite image preprocessing</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/15/rgee_02_io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/15/rgee_02_io/</guid>
      <description>Image preprocessing (i.e. download, reprojection, mosaicking, resize, bad pixels control and composite) has always been a time-consuming activity. Although R offers incredible open-source “API packages” to easily get geospatial resources (modistsp, getSpatialData, elevation, landsat and so on …), these still require that users count with competent computers (and high-end for users that want to analysis large areas).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rgee example #1: Creating static and interactive maps</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/10/rgee_01_worldmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/10/rgee_01_worldmap/</guid>
      <description>Scientific and data analytics are constantly wrangling data and creating visualizations to explain their results. If you are working with structured data, R packages like tidyverse or data.table are probably making your life very pleasant. But what happens for unstructured spatial data?. For instance, if your boss (advisor) asks you to dig through a giant pile of MODIS images, what R package would you use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raster resampling in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/05/resample/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/05/resample/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction A typical workflow for earth analysts always will have to do with several spatial data sources (e.g. Sentinel, MODIS and Landsat) each one with a particular extent and pixel resolution. Resampling is the technique used to homogenize these spatial attributes.
Image obtained from here
 This post demonstrates how easy and incredibly fast is resampling gridded data in R using either the raster and gdalUtils packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>